Jacob Moore

Full Stack Web Developer

Extremely self motivated Boston based Software Developer specializing in Web Development. Proficient in JavaScript, MeteorJS, HTML and CSS, as well as the ability to communicate effectively in a team setting, and possessing a strong willingness to learn.

857-888-7231

Everett, MA, USA

www.jacobmoore.website

github.com/jmooree30

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Development Intern CompanyWide

03/2018 - 09/2018

Boston, MA

CompanyWide is a SaaS platform for construction industry career building Achievements/Tasks

- Made use of JavaScript, Meteor, HTML, CSS and MongoDB to create and improve website features.
- Designed and implemented the ability for users to create and download a PDF copy of their resumes.
- Utilized the Google Maps API to create a map and plot the locations of current job listings based off of the longitude and latitudes gathered with the Geocode API.
- Developed various custom HTML templates that are emailed to companies and workers.
- Worked in an Agile environment development cycle with a team of 5 developers both on site and remotely.
- Integrated the Stripe payment system to charge users for job postings along with the functionality to refund payments.
- Extended on the job listings filtering algorithm by adding the ability to look up listings based on a type of trade.

Lead Welder

Riverside Sheet Metal

02/2014 - Present

Medford, MA

Custom Architectural Metal Fabrication

Achievements/Tasks

- Work as a team with five other fabricators to complete projects worth upwards of \$100,000.
- Oversee the training of apprentice metal fabricators and welders.
- Program and maintain two Baileigh Hydraulic Press Brakes and accompanying touch screen integration systems.

EDUCATION

Bunker Hill Community College

Computer Science

2015 - 2016

Boston, MA

The Odin Project

Open source web development curriculum

01/2017 - 02/2018

SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

Chess

 Wrote a fully functional two player command line version of chess in Ruby. Implemented advanced game mechanics such as pawn promotion, castling, el passant.

Weather App

Simple, straightforward application utilizing the Openweathermap API. Receives data for displaying the current weather for any given zip code in USA, using Javascript. Features include a 5 day forecast and different backgrounds dependent on the time of day.

Facebook Clone

 The project is written with the Ruby on Rails framework. All user authentications were done using Devise with added Sign in functionality, implemented using the industry standard OAuth for further authorization protocols. Featured fully functioning profile page with avatar, and news feed with all major expected functionalities of its predecessor included.

Portfolio

 The website showcases my programming skill set, blog posts, GitHub contributions, and hobbies. The sites frontend was built with React and communicates with a REST-API constructed with Nodejs and Express.

ACHIEVEMENTS

The Odin Project (01/2017 - 02/2018)

I completed 57 different coding projects and finished 100% of the curriculum's material in less than a year, while maintaining a full time job. I am exceptionally proud of this accomplishment